Guide to the New York Times Company records. Arthur Hays Sulzberger papers
New York Public Library
- Series II. Subjects, 1823, 1858, 1875, 1891, 1895, 1900-1910, 1916-1972, 1978-1999, n.d; 210.75 boxes, 9 volumes
  - WABF, 1954 (Box 270, Folder 10)
  - Waldorf-Astoria Hotel, 1954-1957 (Box 270, Folder 11)
  - Wall Street Journal, 1949-1961 (Box 270, Folder 12)
  - Wanamaker, John, Stores, 1953-1957 (Box 270, Folder 13)
  - WAPO (Chattanooga)
  - War Bonds
    - General, 1941-1946 (Box 270, Folder 14)
    - Medal, undated (Box 279)
  - War Debts, 1928-1931, 1945 (Box 270, Folder 15)
  - War Labor Board
  - War Production Board, 1942-1945 (Box 270, Folder 16)
    Includes letters and memoranda about the wartime restrictions on manpower and the use of raw materials in the newspaper industry. AHS served on the advisory committee for the industry.
  - Washington Bureau, 1932-1965 (Box 270, Folder 17-20)
    Includes correspondence and memoranda about staff additions and replacements, salaries, assignments, and other administrative matters, the Bureau's space and furnishings, and bureau's relations with government officials.
  - Washington Post, 1939, 1953-1964 (Box 271, Folder 1)
  - Washington Star (D. C.), 1938, 1945-1965 (Box 271, Folder 2)
  - Washington Star (N. J.), 1938 (Box 271, Folder 3)
  - Washington Times-Herald, 1949-1951 (Box 271, Folder 4)
  - Waste, 1956 (Box 271, Folder 5)
  - Weather, 1934-1962 (Box 271, Folder 6-7)
  - Weather Balloons
  - Webb & Knapp, Inc.
  - Wedding of AHS, 1917 (Box 271, Folder 8)
  - Welcome Wagon, 1960-1962 (Box 271, Folder 9)
  - Welfare Council of New York City, 1925-1955 (Box 271, Folder 10)
  - Wells College, 1951 (Box 271, Folder 11)
  - West Point
  - West Side Association of Commerce
    - General, 1952-1957 (Box 271, Folder 12)
    - Award to AHS, 1957 (Box 291, Folder 9)
  - Western Edition, 1954-1966 (Box 271, Folder 13-16)
    Includes letters, memoranda, clippings, and other documents about plans for and the start of the Western Edition, its staff, production method, circulation, reactions of readers and competitors, its demise in 1964, and Andrew Fisher's summary of the project which was prepared in 1965 as background for AHS's oral history interview at Columbia University.
  - Western Union Telegraph Co., 1947 (Box 271, Folder 17)
  - Western World, 1957 (Box 271, Folder 18)
  - White, William Allen, Foundation
  - Who's Who in America, 1957 (Box 271, Folder 19)
  - Who's Who in World Jewry, 1952-1953 (Box 271, Folder 20)
  - Wide World News Photo Service, Inc.
    These folders contain memoranda, letters, clippings, photographs, and other documents about the NYT's photographic service, its facsimile transmission of photographs, subscription contracts and rates, equipment and installation, the quality of the photographs, competition with the Associated Press, staffing and finances, contracts with the Army Signal Corps for transmission equipment, the sale of the company to the Associated Press, Bruce Rae's report on closing down the remaining commercial photographic operations in Europe, and a 1965 review of the company's history, prepared as background material for AHS's oral history interview at Columbia University.
    - 1942-1950, 1965 (Box 271, Folder 21)
    - 1928-1941 (Box 272, Folder 1-7)
  - Wilkinson Sword, Ltd., 1962-1963 (Box 272, Folder 8)
  - Will of Adolph S. Ochs, 1935, 1946 (Box 272, Folder 9)
    Includes the Company Secretary's record copy of ASO's will annotated to show disposition of each bequest, memoranda on bequests of cash and NYT's stock, AHS's letter transmitting bequests to staff at Abenia, and correspondence about probate in Tennessee.
  - Will of AHS, 1928, 1948-1965 (Box 272, Folder 10)
    Includes correspondence with Edward S. Greenbaum about additions and changes.
  - Williams, Walter, Memorial Journalism Foundation, 1936-1941 (Box 272, Folder 11)
  - Williamsburg, Va.
  - Wilson, Woodrow, Centennial Celebration Commission
  - Wilson, Woodrow, Foundation
    These folders include material on the Woodrow Wilson Centennial Celebration Commission, the Woodrow Wilson Memorial Commission, and the project to publish the papers of Woodrow Wilson. AHS was a director of the Foundation from 1954 to 1957, was on the executive committee of the Centennial Celebration Commission, was appointed by John F. Kennedy to the Memorial Commission, and was interested in and contributed to the publication project. The records in these folders comprise correspondence and reports about meetings, projects relating to Wilson's birth centennial and birthplace, plans for a memorial, publication of the papers, fund-raising, NYT articles about Wilson, and the activities of these organizations.
    - 1957-1966 (Box 272, Folder 12-13)
    - 1954-1956 (Box 273, Folder 1-2)
  - Wilson, Woodrow, Memorial Commission
  - Winners and Sinners
  - Wire Services
  - Wired Music, Inc., 1936 (Box 273, Folder 3)
  - Wirephoto Service
  - Wisdom Magazine, 1954-1967 (Box 273, Folder 4)
  - Wise, Dr., Farm (North College Hill, Cincinnati), 1924 (Box 273, Folder 5)
  - Wise, Isaac Mayer (SS), 1944 (Box 273, Folder 6)
  - WMCA, 1941-1946, 1959 (Box 273, Folder 7-9)
    Includes letters and memoranda about the NYT's arrangements to broadcast hourly news bulletins over WMCA, problems with announcers, timing, and omission of broadcasts, adjacent sponsored programs and commercials, and termination of the arrangement.
  - Women
  - Women's National Press Club, 1950, 1954 (Box 273, Folder 10)
  - Women's News, 1935, 1945-1967 (Box 273, Folder 11-12)
    Includes memoranda about the coverage of women's news, allocation of a separate page, staffing, page layout and design, illustrations, the replacement of Elizabeth Clark French as editor by Elizabeth Penrose Howkins (1954), the controversy between Howkins and Lester Markel (1959), and Charlotte Curtis' appointment as editor (1965).
  - Women's Suffrage
  - Wood, Field and Stream
  - Wood Newspaper Machinery Corporation
  - Woolworth, Inc., 1942 (Box 273, Folder 13)
  - Works Progress Administration (WPA), 1936-1937 (Box 273, Folder 14)
  - World (Newspaper), 1961 (Box 273, Folder 15)
  - World Affairs Workshop, 1965-1966 (Box 273, Folder 16)
  - World Brotherhood, 1953-1954 (Box 273, Folder 17)
  - World Government
  - World Journal Tribune, 1966-1967 (Box 273, Folder 18)
  - World News Summarized, 1948 (Box 273, Folder 19)
  - World Rehabilitation Fund, 1955-1957 (Box 274, Folder 1)
  - World Statistical Congress, 1947 (Box 274, Folder 2)
  - World War I, 1946 (Box 274, Folder 3)
    Includes correspondence about the controversial NYT's September 16, 1918 editorial favoring separate peace talks with Austria.
  - World War II, 1938-1961 (Box 274, Folder 4-9)
    These folders contain letters, memoranda, clippings, and other documents about news coverage of the war and related events, the war effort, peace proposals, and the NYT's editorial positions and AHS's personal views. Includes correspondence about the American Memorial Chapel in St. Paul's Cathedral, London (1952-1961), memoranda about the time of the Japanese attacks on Pearl Harbor and Clark Field, the Philippines (1950), letters, memoranda, and clippings about Edward Kennedy's premature release of the news of Germany's surrender (1945-1947), AHS's reply to a question about the war's effects on newspapers (1945), correspondence about AHS's view that the Lend-Lease declaration committed the United States to war (1945, 1956), AHS's letter to Ruth Sulzberger about war aims and peace plans (1945), AHS's memorandum on need for the United States to support Britain's and the Soviet Union's security aims, correspondence about AHS's view about Lend-Lease (1944), letter from the War Department requesting interviews with correspondents returning from overseas, James Reston's suggestions for staffing up for the expected invasion, AHS's memorandum outlining a peace plan based on the initial restoration of the 1931 borders and related correspondence (1943), the War Department's request for NYT's maps, photographs, and the use of Cyrus Sulzberger's unpublished report on the military situation in Russia, AHS's report to Dwight D. Eisenhower on American troops in England, correspondence about German activities in Latin America, memoranda about an effort at the NYT to coordinate fund-raising for various wartime causes (1942), Arthur Krock's and Charles Hurd's memorandum about conversations with Cordell Hull and George Marshall on negotiations with Japan, memorandum about correspondents detained in Axis nations (1941), correspondence about German activities in Latin America (1939-1941), letters to AHS about conditions in occupied France (1940), AHS's memorandum outlining his views about American involvement in the war (1939), and AHS's notes on confidential conversations with William Christian Bullitt, Jr., on May 17, 1938 and May 10, 1939.
  - World's Fairs (New York), 1936-1940, 1958-1967 (Box 274, Folder 10)
  - World's Work Magazine
  - WPIX
  - WQXR, 1935-1968 (Box 275-276)
    These folders contain memoranda, reports, letters, and other documents about all aspects of WQXR's operations, starting with the earliest investigations of the radio station by the NYT in 1935 and ending with the retirement of Elliott Sanger in 1967 and of Norman McGee in 1968. They concern chiefly the station's music programming (especially the performance of Mozart and of modern music, both of which AHS detested), the news broadcasts and use of NYT staff and material, the policy on advertising and its juxtaposition with news broadcasts, the quality of announcements and commercials, the Program Guide, the station's function in advertising and promoting the NYT, its finances, its equipment and technical operation, and the Rural Radio Network (later called the QXR Network), comprising stations carrying WQXR's programs. Includes preparations to separate programs of WQXR-AM and WQXR-FM (1966), AHS's retirement as chairman of the board, his replacement by Sanger, and Ivan Veit's appointment as president, Sanger's memorandum recalling the NYT's acquisition of WQXR (1964), special broadcasts during the International Typographical Union strike, and controversy with AOS, John Oakes, and Sanger over retaining expanded news and editorial broadcasts after the strike (1962-1963), Sanger's assignment to the International Edition in Paris (1961), new transmitting facility in Maspeth, new by-laws (1952-1954), interference from other stations, controversy with Douglas A. McKinnon (1948-1949), Jack Gould's reports on programs and policies, Nicholas Roosevelt's memorandum on key personnel (1945-1947), political advertising, correspondence about the NYT's acquisition of WQXR (1944), correspondence and reports about the station and its principal owner and president, John V. L. Hogan, and correspondence about the NYT's sponsorship of a program on the station (1935-1938).
  - Yaddo
  - Yale University, 1936-1959 (Box 277, Folder 1)
  - Yalta Conference, 1945, 1955 (Box 277, Folder 2)
  - Yank, 1942 (Box 277, Folder 3)
  - Year, 1952 (Box 277, Folder 4)
  - Yorkshire Post, 1953-1954 (Box 277, Folder 5)
  - Young & Rubicam, Inc., 1953 (Box 277, Folder 6)
  - Young Men's Christian Association
  - Young Men's Real Estate Association of New York, 1955-1956 (Box 277, Folder 7)
  - Young Presidents' Organization, 1956 (Box 277, Folder 8)
  - Youth Forums, 1946-1959 (Box 277, Folder 9)
    Incldues memoranda and letters about the radio and television program produced by the NYT, meetings with alumni of the program, a competitive program offered by the Herald Tribune, and awards for the program and its moderator, Dorothy Gordon.
  - Yugoslavia, 1932, 1941-1949, 1954-1959, 1966 (Box 277, Folder 10)
  - Zenger, John Peter, Awards
  - Zenger Memorial
    AHS was deeply involved, with James Wright Brown, in efforts to create a memorial to John Peter Zenger. These folders contain letters, memoranda, pamphlets, and other documents about the campaign to have the Memorial at St. Paul's Church in Eastchester, N. Y. and to have the church declared a national shrine, the plans for the Zenger Memorial there, fund-raising efforts, the decision to establish the Memorial in the Federal Hall Memorial, the exhibits there, the annual Bill of Rights ceremonies at St. Paul's Church, the neglect of the church and grounds and efforts to raise funds for its maintenance and restoration, and the personnel, activities and eventual disbanding of the Zenger Memorial Fund Committee. Included are the various documents giving the history of Zenger's trial and of St. Paul's Church, the rededication of the church in 1942, at which AHS spoke, the arrangements with the National Park Service for the Federal Hall Memorial (1944), the dedication ceremonies there, at which AHS spoke (1953) and correspondence about the exhibits there (1953).
    - General
      - 1951-1965 (Box 277, Folder 11-15)
      - 1936-1950 (Box 278, Folder 1-9)
    - Architectural drawings, 1946 (Box 293, Folder 10)
  - Zeta Beta Tau, 1958 (Box 278, Folder 10)
  - Zionism